Guide to the Brooklyn slide collection V1984.001
Brooklyn Historical Society
Brooklyn slide collection
1963-1978
Brooklyn Historical Society
V1984.001
3.2 Linear Feet in three boxes.
A collection of slides depicting various items from the collections of the Brooklyn Historical Society as well as Brooklyn neighborhoods, parks, and monuments.
Conditions Governing Access
Open to users without restriction.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
This artifical collection was assembled by LIHS staff through a variety of sources, dates unknown.
Existence and Location of Copies
Item-level description and digital versions of images from the collection are available for searching via the image database in the library under the object ID prefix V1984.1.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged by object ID. Items without an object ID are arranged by subject.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
The collection's digital surrogates should be used in place of the originals whenever possible.
Scope and Contents
The Brooklyn slide collection dates from 1963 to 1978 and contains 1,471 items. Slides in this collection are duplicates of original photographs, illustrations, manuscripts, maps, museum objects, and books from the collections of the Brooklyn Historical Society and other sources. Subjects include aerial views, American Revolution and Battle of Long Island sites, the Army, banks, bridges, indigenous people in Brooklyn, churches, clubs, fire companies, post offices, hotels, docks, mills, the Navy, portraits, schools, neighborhoods, and public transit, and the Long Island Historical Society (now known as the Brooklyn Historical Society). In addition to these subjects, the collection contains tax photographs of buildings along Flatbush Avenue and cross streets from Downtown Brooklyn to Prospect Heights. Neighborhoods documented in the collection include Bay Ridge, Bedford-Stuyvesant, Downtown Brooklyn, Brooklyn Heights, Cobble Hill, Coney Island, Flatbush, East New York, Fort Greene, Gravesend, Park Slope, and Williamsburg. Images of Prospect Park, Grand Army Plaza, and Green-Wood Cemetery are also included.
Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.); Color slides
- Slides by Object ID
  Scope and Contents
  This series consists of slides that have been individually numbered and described in the library's image database.
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
  The digitized images and descriptions of the items in this series are available to view on site at the library.
  - V1984.1.1-160 (Box 1)
  - V1984.1.161-320 (Box 1, Box 2)
  - V1984.1.321-480 (Box 1, Box 3)
  - V1984.1.481-663 (Box 1, Box 4)
  - V1984.1.664-852 (Box 1, Box 5)
  - V1984.1.853-1020 (Box 1, Box 6)
  - V1984.1021-1180 (Box 2, Box 1)
  - V1984.1.1181-1340 (Box 2)
  - V1984.1.1341-1425, 1440-1471 (Box 2, Box 3)
- Slides by subject
  - Business, Commerce, Advertisements (Box 2, Box 3-4)
  - Fire department (Box 2, Box 4)
  - Long Island (Box 2, Box 4-5)
  - Long Island, 1974 August (Box 2, Box 4)
  - Long Island: Maps (Box 2, Box 5)
  - Long Island: Nassau (Box 2, Box 6)
  - Long Island: People (Box 2, Box 5)
  - Long Island: Suffolk (Box 2, Box 6)
  - Prospect Park, snowy, 1973 February (Box 2, Box 5)
  - Queens (Box 2, Box 6)
  - Queens: Fort Totten (Box 2, Box 6)
  - Recreation (Box 2, Box 6)
  - Shipping (Box 2, Box 6)
  - Transportation (Box 2, Box 6)
  - Venues (Box 2, Box 6)
- Other materials
  - Unnumbered slides (Box 3, Box 1)
  - Prints (Box 3)